Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。我是Catherine，今天我们要打一个电话。
today we're making a phone call. That's right, we are making a special type of phone call.
没错，我们要打一种特殊的电话。
We're making a collect call. So, we will explain what this means. Let's listen to the dialogue.
我们要打一个对方付费电话。所以，我们会解释这是什么意思。让我们听一下对话。
See if you can more or less guess what a collect call means and we'll be right back.
看看你是否能大致猜出对方付费电话是什么意思，我们马上回来。
This is the operator. How may I help you? Yes, I would like to make a collect call.
这里是接线员。有什么可以帮您的？是的，我想打一个对方付费电话。
Okay sir, please dial the number. Now, please state your name. Tommy. Please wait a moment.
好的先生，请拨号码。现在，请说出您的名字。Tommy。请稍等。
Hello, you have a collect call from Tommy. Would you like to accept the charges? Yes,
您好，您有一个来自Tommy的对方付费电话。您愿意接受费用吗？是的，
of course. Dad? Yeah, Tommy. What happened? Are you okay? Yeah, dad. Everything is okay.
当然。爸爸？嗯，Tommy。发生什么事了？你还好吗？是的，爸爸。一切都好。
I'm calling you because I want to know if it's okay for me to go to my friend's house
我打电话是想问您，我今天放学后可以去朋友家吗？
today after school. Yeah, sure. No problem. You scared me to death. I've told you to make
好的，当然可以。没问题。你吓死我了。我告诉过你只有在紧急情况下才能打
a collect call in case of an emergency only. Why didn't you call me from your mobile phone?
对方付费电话。你为什么不用手机给我打电话？
I ran out of credit and I also didn't have 25 cents for the pay phone. Sorry, dad.
我话费用完了，而且我也没有25美分打公用电话。对不起，爸爸。
Alright, so we're back. We've got a number of words and phrases to look at. Let's check
好了，我们回来了。我们有一些单词和短语要学习。让我们先看看
out our words in Language Takeaway first.
我们的“语言要点”中的单词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, so as we mentioned, we are making a collect call. So what exactly is a collect
好的，正如我们提到的，我们在打一个对方付费电话。那么到底什么是对方付费
call?
电话？
Alright, well a collect call is a phone call you make when you don't have any money and
好的，对方付费电话是指当你没有钱时打的电话，
the phone company charges the person who answers the phone.
电话公司会向接电话的人收费。
Okay.
好的。
So if I call my mom with a collect call, my mom pays.
所以如果我打对方付费电话给我妈，那是我妈付钱。
Not you.
不是你。
Not me.
不是我。
And you can do this pretty much from any phone, right?
而且你几乎可以用任何电话这么做，对吧？
That's right. You can do this from any phone. Normally people use pay phones to do this.
没错。你可以用任何电话这么做。通常人们用公用电话来打这种电话。
But there is one condition that is important with the collect call. The person who answers
但对方付费电话有一个重要条件。接电话的人
the phone, they have to say that it's okay that they pay. You can't just use this with
必须说他们同意付钱。你不能随便对任何人用这个。
anybody.
对任何人。
Okay, very good. So actually when the guy was making this collect call, the operator
好的，很好。所以实际上当那个人打对方付费电话时，接线员
asked him to dial the number.
让他拨号。
Okay, so this is an important verb that we have with making a telephone call. You make
好的，这是打电话时一个重要的动词。你打电话，
a call, but with the number, the phone number, you actually have to dial it.
但对于号码，电话号码，你实际上必须拨号。
And that comes from those old phones where you don't push the numbers, you pull them.
这来自那些老式电话，你不是按数字，而是拉它们。
Yeah, you have to spin the little wheel.
是的，你得转动那个小轮盘。
Yeah, there are circles and you pull the numbers and spin the wheel around. But the verb now
对，有圆盘，你拉数字然后转动轮盘。但现在这个动词
is to dial a number.
就是拨号。
To dial a number. That's right. Okay, so you dial your number and well actually as we said,
拨号。没错。好的，所以你拨你的号码，实际上就像我们说的，
you're making this collect call because maybe you don't have any money. In this case, sometimes
你打对方付费电话可能是因为你没钱。在这种情况下，有时候
in your mobile phone, you have what we call credit.
在你的手机里，我们有所谓的余额。
This is an important word. This is a noun. You have it or you don't have it. On my phone,
这是个重要的词。这是个名词。你有它或者你没有它。在我的手机上，
for example, I have a lot of credit. But maybe if I don't have any credit, I run out of credit,
比如，我有很多话费。但如果我没有话费了，话费用完了，
I don't have any money left, I can't make a phone call.
我就没钱了，打不了电话。
That's right. So this is what it means when you have credit in your phone. It means that
没错。所以这就是手机里有话费的意思，也就是说
you have some money with the telephone company. So when you make a call, they discount it
你在电话公司存了一些钱。所以当你打电话时，他们会从里面扣钱。
from there. But if you don't have any more credit, you can't make any phone calls.
但如果话费用完了，你就打不了电话了。
Exactly. So basically credit represents money.
正是这样。所以基本上话费就代表钱。
That's right. Okay, and as you said, a collect call, you usually make it from a pay phone.
没错。好的，就像你说的，对方付费电话通常是在公用电话上打的。
So what is a pay phone?
那什么是公用电话呢？
Okay, well, we have phones at people's houses. Those are regular phones. And we have cell
好的，嗯，人们家里有电话，那是普通电话。还有
phones which you can carry around. Well, pay phones are public phones that you have to
可以随身携带的手机。而公用电话是公共电话，你需要
use money in order to make a call on.
投钱才能打电话。
Okay, so usually you will see these at airports, for example.
好的，所以通常你会在机场之类的地方看到它们。
Airports, train stations, any big public place where people need to use phones. They're less
机场、火车站，任何人们需要打电话的大型公共场所。现在有些地方
common now in some places. But basically, you have to put the coins, the money coins
不太常见了。但基本上，你得把硬币投进
into the phone to get the phone to work. If you don't have any money, you can't make a
电话里才能让它工作。如果你没钱，就
call.
打不了电话。
Yeah, that's right. Okay, so four key words there. Why don't we take a break and listen
是的，没错。好的，这里有四个关键词。我们休息一下，再听一遍
to the dialogue again.
对话吧。
This is the operator. How may I help you?
这里是接线员。请问有什么可以帮您？
Yes, I would like to make a collect call.
是的，我想打一个对方付费电话。
Okay, sir. Please dial the number. Now, please state your name.
好的，先生。请拨号。现在，请说出您的姓名。
Tommy.
汤米。
Please wait a moment.
请稍等一下。
Hello, you have a collect call from Tommy. Would you like to accept the charges?
你好，你有一个来自Tommy的对方付费电话。你愿意接受付费吗？
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
Dad?
爸爸？
Yeah, Tommy. What happened? Are you okay?
是啊，汤米。发生什么事了？你还好吗？
Yeah, Dad. Everything is okay. I'm calling you because I want to know if it's okay for
嗯，爸。一切都好。我打给你是因为我想知道是否可以……
me to go to my friend's house today after school.
我今天放学后要去朋友家。
Yeah, sure. No problem. You scared me to death. I've told you to make a collect call in case
好的，没问题。你吓死我了。我跟你说过要打对方付费电话以防万一。
of an emergency only. Why didn't you call me from your mobile phone?
仅在紧急情况下才能用。你为什么不用手机给我打电话？
I ran out of credit and I also didn't have 25 cents for the payphone. Sorry, Dad.
我话费用完了，连25美分打公用电话都没有。对不起，爸爸。
All right, now we're going to talk a little bit more about the phrases we found in this
好的，现在我们来进一步聊聊在这段对话里出现的短语。
dialogue on Fluency Builder.
对话来自流利度训练。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So this first phrase is a phrase that you might encounter in many different situations,
所以第一个短语是一个你在很多不同场合都可能遇到的短语。
but today's situation is making a collect call. So we heard this phrase, please state
但是今天的情况是打一个对方付费电话。所以我们听到了这个短语，请说明
your name.
你的名字。
That's right. So you have a verb here, to state your name, state your age, and that
没错。所以这里有一个动词，用来陈述你的名字、陈述你的年龄。
basically means to tell us, tell me or tell us what is your name.
基本上就是说，告诉我们，告诉我或者告诉我们你的名字是什么。
That's right. So if I say, hey, you, state your name.
没错。所以如果我说，嘿，你，报上名来。
That means I have to say my name, Marco, for example.
这意味着我必须说出我的名字，比如 Marco。
So you can use it for name, for age.
所以你可以用它来表示名字、年龄。
Yes. State your birthday, please. So this is often what we have to do when we're on
是的。请说出你的生日。所以这通常是我们需要做的事情，比如在……
the phone with a service company. So the bank will ask us, what is your, you know, state
与一家服务公司通电话。所以银行会问我们，你的，嗯，州是哪个。
your birthday, please, or state your last name or state your phone number. They want
你的生日，请，或者说出你的姓氏，或者说出你的电话号码。他们想要。
to confirm our personal information.
确认一下我们的个人信息。
Okay. And well, as we heard it, so once you do all this, you make a collect call. The
好的。那么，就像我们听到的那样，一旦你完成了这些步骤，你就可以拨打一个对方付费电话。
person on the other side has to accept, and this is when the operator said, would you
对方必须接受，这时接线员说：“您愿意吗？”
like to accept the charges?
您愿意支付费用吗？
In this case, to accept the charges means to offer to pay. Okay. So if you accept the
在这种情况下，accept the charges 的意思是主动提出支付费用。好的。所以如果你接受这个
charges, that means that the phone company will ask you for money when your bill comes.
charges，意思是电话公司会在你的账单寄来时向你收费。
That's right. So you accept to be charged with money or you accept the charges that
没错。所以你是同意被收费，还是同意这些费用？
come with this telephone call.
跟着这个电话一起来。
That's right.
没错。
And now the dad finally says, are you okay? You know, is everything all right? And apparently
现在爸爸终于开口问：“你还好吗？你知道的，一切都好吗？”显然——
it was a very trivial thing. He just called to make sure that he can go to his friend's
这是一件非常琐碎的小事。他只是打电话确认一下能不能去朋友家。
house and the dad said, you scared me to death.
房子，然后爸爸说：“你吓死我了。”
Okay. Parents often use this phrase in English. This means you had me very worried. I was
好的。父母经常用这个英语短语。意思是“你让我非常担心”。我当时
so worried. So you scared me to death. That doesn't mean that the father died.
这么担心。你真是吓死我了。这并不意味着父亲真的死了。
Right.
没错。
It means he was very, very, very scared.
意思是他非常、非常、非常害怕。
Right. Exactly. So it's a phrase a little bit, obviously with exaggeration, but very
对，正是。所以这个短语有点夸张，但很常见。
common to hear. You scared me to death. You scared me a lot.
你吓死我了。你吓了我一大跳。
Yes.
是的。
And why did he scare him to death? Because he told his son to make a collect call in
那他为什么把他吓个半死？因为他告诉儿子只有在紧急情况下才能打对方付费电话。
case of an emergency only.
只有在紧急情况下。
Okay. So this phrase in case of an emergency is a fixed phrase. You can see this on the
好的。所以“in case of an emergency”这个短语是固定搭配。你可以在
metro, you can see this on the bus, but also you can hear this in conversation. And so
地铁上看到，也可以在公交车上看到，而且在对话中也能听到。所以
in case of an emergency means only when there is an emergency situation, a fire, an accident,
“in case of an emergency”意思是只有在紧急情况发生时，比如火灾、事故，
something like that.
类似的情况。
That's right. Maybe on a train you have seen or on an airplane, you have a big red button
没错。也许你在火车上或飞机上见过，有一个大红按钮
or a lever that says pull in case of emergency.
或拉杆，上面写着“紧急情况下拉动”。
That means don't pull it now, but pull it if there's a serious problem.
意思是现在别拉，但如果有严重问题就拉。
That's right.
没错。
So the father says, you know what? I told you only make a collect call in case of an
所以父亲说：你知道吗？我告诉过你只有在紧急情况下才能打对方付费电话。
emergency. That means if there's an accident, if the boy's in the hospital, if there is
意思是如果有事故，如果男孩在医院，如果
something serious happening, then it's okay to charge to make this collect call. But other
有严重的事情发生，那么打对方付费电话是可以的。但其他
times like, you know, you forgot your wallet. That's not an emergency.
时候，比如你忘了带钱包，那不算紧急情况。
Yeah. All right. Very good. So why don't we listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll
是的。好的，非常好。那我们最后再听一遍对话，然后我们
be right back.
马上回来。
This is the operator. How may I help you?
这里是接线员。请问有什么可以帮您？
Yes, I would like to make a collect call.
是的，我想打一个对方付费电话。
Okay, sir. Please dial the number. Now, please state your name.
好的，先生。请拨号。现在，请说出您的姓名。
Tommy.
汤米。
Please wait a moment.
请稍等一下。
Hello. You have a collect call from Tommy. Would you like to accept the charges?
你好。你有一个来自汤米的对方付费电话。你愿意接受付费吗？
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
Dad?
爸爸？
Yeah, Tommy. What happened? Are you okay?
是啊，汤米。发生什么事了？你还好吗？
Yeah, Dad. Everything is okay. I'm calling you because I want to know if it's okay for
嗯，爸。一切都好。我打给你是因为我想知道能不能……
me to go to my friend's house today after school.
我今天放学后要去朋友家。
Yeah, sure. No problem. You scared me to death. I've told you to make a collect call in case
好的，没问题。你吓死我了。我跟你说过要打对方付费电话以防万一。
of an emergency only. Why didn't you call me from your mobile phone?
仅在紧急情况下使用。你为什么不用手机给我打电话？
I ran out of credit and I also didn't have 25 cents for the payphone. Sorry, Dad.
我话费用完了，连投币电话的25分钱都没有。对不起，爸爸。
So making a collect call, very common thing as well. This is the scenario you will find
所以打对方付费电话，也是非常常见的事情。这就是你会遇到的情况。
in the United States, for example, if you go to a payphone, you don't have any money,
例如在美国，如果你去公用电话亭，身上没带钱，
you want to call your friend, the tour guide, the airport, anything, you can make a collect
你想给你的朋友、导游、机场或任何人打电话，都可以打对方付费电话。
call.
call. 打电话。
That's right. And this is something that is, like I said, becoming less common with cell
没错。而且就像我说的，随着手机普及，这种情况越来越少了。
phones. But generally speaking, if you don't have any money and you have an emergency situation
电话。但一般来说，如果你没钱又遇到紧急情况，
or you need to call someone, it's very important, then you can make a collect call. You dial
或者需要打电话给某人，这非常重要，那么你可以打对方付费电话。你拨
O for zero for the operator and you say, I want to make a collect call. And they will
0 找接线员，然后说，我想打一个对方付费电话。他们会
ask you these important questions. And then what the other person hears is, you know,
问你这些重要的问题。然后对方听到的是，你知道，
Catherine would like to make a collect call.
凯瑟琳想打一个对方付费电话。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
Will you accept the charges? And you know, if you're my mother, you'll say yes, of course.
你愿意接受费用吗？你知道，如果你是我妈妈，你肯定会说，当然愿意。
That's right. Now, as you said, payphones, they used to be all over the place and you
没错。现在，就像你说的，公用电话以前到处都是，你
would have to put in a quarter. This is why the kid said that he didn't have any money
得投一个25美分硬币。这就是为什么那个孩子说他没钱
for the payphone. But now you don't really see too many payphones. Everyone's got mobile
用公用电话。但现在你很少看到公用电话了。每个人都有手机
phones.
了。
That's right. And payphones are less and less common, although a lot of people like to use
没错。公用电话越来越少见，尽管很多人喜欢用
payphones just because they're private, not tracked.
公用电话，因为它们私密，不会被追踪。
And yeah, but what I found is that the airports now, you can't use a payphone with quarters
是啊，但我发现现在机场里，你不能用25美分硬币或现金来用公用电话。
or money. Now you got to use a credit card to use a payphone.
现在你得用信用卡才能用公用电话。
That's right. It's become so expensive that you have to swipe your credit card to use
没错。它变得这么贵，你得刷信用卡才能用
the payphone. So it's a changing world, Marco.
公用电话。所以世界在变，马可。
Now, can we make international collect calls?
现在，我们能打国际对方付费电话吗？
I don't think so. I think it's just America.
我觉得不行。我想只有美国可以。
Okay. Well, this is a very interesting topic. Obviously, we will see if in your country
好的。嗯，这是个非常有趣的话题。显然，我们会看看在你的国家是否
you can make collect calls or how do you make a call to someone if you don't have any money?
你可以打对方付费电话，或者如果你没钱怎么给别人打电话？
That's a good question. So let us know. Our website is EnglishPod.com.
这是个好问题。那就告诉我们吧。我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you guys there. Bye.
我们到时候见。再见。
Bye.
再见。